## **Enrique García Cota**

Project Manager at Splendeo Innovación

Madrid, Spain (+34) 666901806 egarcia@splendeo.es

### **Profile Summary**

# Client-facing skills / Project management skills / Global scale projects (different timezones, outsourcing)

Strong technical background, specialty on web-based projects.

Native Spanish, nearly bilingual English, and fluent French. Working experience on the 3 languages.

#### Education

**Real Time Major** on the *Institut Supérieur d'Électronique de Paris (ISEP)* – February 2002 **Computer Science Degree** on the University of Seville – September 2003

### Working Experience

#### Colgate & CERN - Development Lead

May 2009 - present Splendeo

Technical lead on a web application company. Most recent projects were two projects developed for Colgate-Palmolive (www.e-storemonitor.com) and the CERN (www.ohwr.org).

- Facilitating business requests (new project and change requests) from initial opening through to the creation of **functional specifications** and **contracts**.
- Working with clients to determine their business requirements, while reporting and tracking project costs
- Providing insight into best way to achieve desired functionality, including assessment of time and cost impacts
- Managing multiple projects at once; across multiple brands and geographical regions.
- · Technologies employed: Ruby on Rails, Drupal, AJAX

# Diageo Eservices - Solution Manager European Lead

July 2007 - April 2009 A

Accentur e

The Solution Manager is involved in the delivery of projects and change requests for the websites that Accenture builds. In detail, the roles and responsibilities include:

- Functional Specifications and Contracts
- Business requirements and project costs.
- · Acting as liaison between development team and the business
- Providing technical project management status, including status reports, issue logs, change control logs
- Sample work: www.johnniewalker.com, www.baileys.com , including all international versions.

Technologies employed: Microsoft Sharepoint.

"In addition Enrique moved to the the position of European Solution Manager Lead on the last quarter of 2008. This involved looking after a team of 2 other Solution Managers based in London and Dublin. He provided pastoral care and looked after progress/status of the team; as well as had involvement in wider engagement tasks and issues."

# Carrefour - Requirements gathering team March 2007 - June 2007 Accentur leader e

I directed a team of 4 people in gathering and documenting requirements for new application.

The main language used on this project was French.

The project required management of a small team, quick learning of the business requirements as well

Enrique García Cota 2010-11-11 1/3

as direct contact with the Client.

## Diageo - Application development and maintenance

**October 2005 - June 2007** 

Accentur

Maintenance and improvement of 2 web applications used for time reporting and cost control.

- Design and implementation of new reports, as well as improvement of existing ones. The timing and budgetary information appearing on those reports was then used by management.
- C# , server javascript, SQL + IIS.

#### **Accenture - Other Assignments**

Feb. 2004 - August 2005

**Accentur** 

····

I've worked on several other assignments in Accenture, including

- Writing documentation about a Siebel installation.
- Working on the PMO office of a complex (+600 people) project.
- · Managing the network of that same project.
- Updating roles by using the SAP Security Module.
- Automating several procedures by using Excel + VBA.

Kondor+/TradeKast - D	evelopment
Internship	-

Feb 2002 - July 2002

Reuters Financial Software

As part of my studies in Paris, I made an internship re-developing some parts of a database import/export library in order to increase its maintainability.

- Intensive C/C++ programming
- · Developing of a new database binding language
- The working environment's language was French, but documents where written in English.

Snecma	<b>Moteurs</b> -	Deve	lopment
Internsh	ip		

**Sept. 2001 - January** 2002

Snecma Moteurs/ISEP

Join project between the ISEP (*Institut Supérieur d'Électronique de Paris*) and SNECMA Moteurs. The project consisted in the study of the viability of an airplane engine's digital control system.

• Network Protocol analysis (Firewire, USB) / Real-time operative systems (QNX, Linux RT) / C prototype

### Training/Continuing Education

Several trainings completed while in Accenture, on subjects including **methodology**, **decision making** and **leadership**.

#### Skills

**Expert** MS Office, **Software Development**, **Expectations & Project Management**, **Reporting** 

HTML, Javascript, Ruby on Rails, VBA, SQL, C, C++

Advance Negotiation, Team management, Client-facing skills, Outsourcing projects

SQL, SQL Server, PostgreSQL, ISS, Apache, CSS, Linux, MS Windows, Prototype.js,

jQuery, SEO, MS MOSS (Sharepoint)

Proficien Rapid Application Management, Test Scripts,

Java, C#, .NET, Web 2.0 protocols, PHP

**Trained** Interface design, Training and performance support,

XSLT, Visual Studio

#### Languages

Native **Spanish** speaker.

Excellent **English** and **French**. I've used both of them as working languages of high technical and managerial complexity. I've also both of them on a client-facing level, for several reasons; from discussing technical details to negotiating project budgets.

### Interests

I'm interested in all new technologies, specially web-related.

My hobbies include science fiction literature, video games and traveling, specially to Europe and Asia. I'm learning to play the guitar and like running and skiing.